the first thing you want to figure out
after you've mentally gotten to that
place where you know you're taking
something on is you you need to set as
your primary goal not to not necessarily
to learn a specific technology or get a
job that's kind of premature you need to
know my opinion you really need to know
what it is you want to do and where you
want to do it and this is a very Zen
activity I've talked about it a lot but
this is something that takes a lot of
soul searching and so I want to go
through through some of the things you
can do to answer those questions because
as you have to answer this question
first otherwise everything else could
potentially be a waste of time even if
you do get the waste of time and you
turn around you realize that's not what
you want to do and I've talked about
that elsewhere that's fine but the more
you can avoid that the better let me
give you one specific successful example
I love this example um somebody that I
helped Mentor is skill stack uh from a
very young age they I I they came in
wanting to do Minecraft servers and
stuff at a very young age and they
stayed with me for several years and
they were able to explore all kinds of
different things they were able to do
security uh it turns out that they
really liked um Computer Engineering and
they taught themselves assembly and you
know they they had experience through
exploration um and just you know
completely unstructured learning a bunch
of different things so by the time it
came to go to college um they were able
to do the tour and fly around and go to
the other colleges and
and evaluate the programs within these
colleges and they knew exactly what they
wanted right they so many people go to
college to just to in a very expensive
way discover what it is they want to be
they Chang Majors five times I changed
mine at least three and they don't know
so they waste a lot of time and whether
you're going to go to college or you're
going to go into a job spending that
time that that that to find out what it
is you want to do and the the specifics
the specifics of where who has the best
program this particular person went to
Carnegie melan they went to MIT they
went to a bunch of places and they end
up going to a state school that had a
better computer engineering program
because they liked the lab there better
than MIT can you believe that but they
knew that they wanted because they had
been doing the research they been
putting in the time to figure out what
it was that they wanted and we're going
to do some more videos here about
specific activities to help you discover
that